· A.I. ENGINEER SPECIALISED IN NLP

Nijmegen, The Netherlands

□ (+31) 6-2529-7625 | Samarpan-rai@live.com | Marww.s-rai.com | Damarpan-rai | Damarpan-rai | Damarpan-rai

"Programnming is about trying to make the future less painful. (Saron Yitbarek)"

Summary.

Self-starter and ever curious to learn new things. I like to challenge myself and improve my skill-set. I like working across domain so I will not shy away from a problem.

Worked in projects ranging from embedded circuit development for a creative agency in Kathmandu (Nepal), API Developer for a startup company in Paris (France), Social Media Manager for Radboud University (Netherlands) to Product Manager for startup company in Nijmegen (Netherlands). I have a diverse background so try to think about problem from various angles before starting to code a single line.

Work Experience

Vartion B.V.Malden, The Netherlands

A.I Engineer (NLP focus)

May. 2020 - Present

- Translate business problem to concrete and scoped computational problem while following Scrum principles
- Annotate and prepare data required for training various models using tools like Prodigy.
- Train state-of-art NLP model to extract rich information from unstructured text using tools like HuggingFace and Pytorch.
- · Deployed trained model in production such that they horizontally scale using Docker and Kubernetes.

GooHoo B.V.

Hatert, The Netherlands

DATA SCIENTIST (FORECASTING FOCUS)

Nov. 2018- Apr. 2020

Nov. 2015 - May. 2016

- Translating abstract business problems to concrete data science problems.
- Research latest work on Retail and Operations management focusing on Demand forecasting for FMG.
- Create data pipelines in R to process and transform data from diverse sources and create dashboards in Shiny to provide actionable business insights.
- Attempt to build algorithm for dynamically pricing multiple products to maximise revenue using AWS's Sagemaker to regularly train and deploy
 model.

WYND Paris, France

WEB INTEGRATION DEVELOPER

- Investigate method to reduce data consumption in POS mobile devices for payment.
- Implement publishing-subscribe based messaging system to allow to cheaply communicate to the devices (reducing cost by 60%).
- Develop API for seamless mobile SDK integration.

Education

Radboud UniversityNijmegen, The Netherlands

B.S. IN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE 2016 - 2020

- Strong focus on cognitive science such intelligence is studied from Brain to machine.
- Active member of study association Cognac
- Graduated with 7.5 on thesis titled "Using Back-Propagation based Highlights as an Explanation in Human Fake News Detection"

Radboud UniversityNijmegen, The Netherlands

HONOURS PROGRAMME 2016 - 2016

- · Critically thinking and discussing about various divisive topics like climate change, euthanasia, and the Al's impact on the society.
- Graduating paper: "Why Artificial Intelligence (AI) is the backbone of Automation?".

TomTom Summer schoolAmsterdam, The Netherlands

Participant 26-30 August 2019

- An intensive week long summer school about the technology that drives the autonomous cars.
- Trained end-to-end model to follow line autonomously.
- Won runner up position for our work.

APRIL 18, 2021 SAMARPAN RAI · RÉSUMÉ 1

Extracurricular Activity

CognacNijmegen, The Netherlands

CHAIRMAN OF INTERNATIONAL STUDENTS' COMMITTEE

2018 - 2019

- · Organised workshop and talks to share international students' experience and tips on how to adjust in Dutch society.
- Planned fun activities for students to explore Dutch cities and learn about local history.

Newcraft 24 Data Challenge

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Participant 7-8 May 2019

- Worked on case for Picnic to answer if weather affects sales.
- · We did not win but learnt valuable lesson about understanding problem and exploring the data before jumping into implementation.

CoderDojo Nijmegen Nijmegen, The Netherlands

MENTOR

July 2018 - May 2019

• Answering coding related question from kids learning to code.

Leisure

Develop Clumper for munging data easily

GitHub

CONTRIBUTOR

2020 - PRESENT

- Implementing new features for loading json(l) data using simple functions.
- Create decorators to apply the same function across multiple places with ease.

Tech and non-tech writing at my own blog

GitHub

WRITER

2019 - PRESENT

· Whenever inspiration strikes, I write about various topics like programming, math, and learning Dutch.

Languages

English

CEFR C2 LEVEL

Dutch

CEFR A2 LEVEL

Nepali

CEFR C2 LEVEL